Paul Dukas: Correspondence with Paul Poujaud
Yale University Music Library
Paul Dukas: Correspondence with Paul Poujaud
1891-1935
Misc. Ms. 288
Yale University Music Library
1.5
(4 boxes)
Correspondence between the French composer and critic Paul Dukas (1865-1935) and his friend Paul Poujaud, a lawyer
Dukas, Paul, 1865-1935
Poujaud, Paul
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open to researchers by appointment. There are no restricted materials in the collection. Please contact the Special Collections staff to schedule an appointment.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased at auction in June 1977.
Arrangement
In 4 series as follows: I. Letters from Dukas to Poujaud. II. Letters from Poujaud to Dukas. III. Letters from others. IV. Miscellaneous items.
Scope and Contents
Paul Dukas's correspondence with Paul Poujaud spans the years 1891 to 1935 and includes over 550 autograph letters between the two men. The correspondence also contains 3 photographs of Dukas and a metronome enregistreur.
Biographical / Historical
Paul Dukas was born in Paris on October 1, 1865. He studied composition at the Paris Conservatoire with Ernest Guiraud; in 1928, Dukas himself became a professor of composition at the Conservatoire. Like Schumann, Debussy, and Thomson, Dukas was a prominent music critic as well as a composer. He composed a variety of works, mostly for orchestra, voice, or piano. He was not prolific, and he destroyed numerous pieces that did not meet his standards. His most frequently performed composition is The Sorcerer's Apprentice. He died in Paris on May 17, 1935.
Paul Poujaud, a lawyer, was friends with Dukas and many other notable French musicians in the early 20th century.
Composers -- Correspondence; Music -- France -- 20th Century
- Letters from Dukas to Poujaud, Series I
  - Inventory (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Letters from Dukas to Poujaud (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Paris, 1891 December 07; 2 pages
      General
      Autograph letter signed, envelope
    - Paris, 1891 December 18; 1 page
      Autograph letter signed
    - Paris, 1892 April 04; 1 page
    - Paris, 1892 October 24; 2 pages
    - St. Cloud, 1893; 1 page
      Autograph card
    - Paris, 1893 February 10; 2 pages
    - Paris, 1894 February 18; 1 page
      Invitation
    - Paris, 1895 February 05; 2 pages
    - Paris, 1895 October 06; 2 pages
    - Paris, 1896 March; 1 page
    - Paris, 1897 January 01; 1 page
    - Paris, 1897 March 07; 1 page
    - Paris, 1898 April; 1 page
  - Letters from Dukas to Poujaud (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Paris, 1901 July; 1 page each
      Autograph letter signed, and Autograph letter signed from A. Dukas
    - Paris, 1901 July 12; 1 page
    - Paris, 1901 December 02; 1 page
    - Paris, 1902 May 02; 1 page
    - Paris, 1902 July 03; 1 page
    - Paris, 1902 August 10; 4 pages
    - Paris, 1903 January; 1 page
    - Paris, 1903 August 30; 1 page
      Autograph postcard signed
    - Bonn, 1903 September 08; 1 page
    - Bonn, 1903 November; 1 page
    - Paris, 1904 February 05; 1 page
    - Paris, 1904 February 12; 1 page
  - Letters from Dukas to Poujaud (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Paris, 1905 January 22; 2 pages
    - Paris, 1905 November 13; 2 pages
    - Paris, 1905 November 18; 1 page
    - Paris, 1905 December 18; 1 page
    - Paris, 1906 March 28; 1 page
    - Paris, 1906 April; 1 page
    - Paris, 1906 April Saturday; 1 page
    - Paris, 1906 June 07; 1 page
    - Paris, 1906 July 28; 4 pages
  - Letters from Dukas to Poujaud (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Paris, 1907 February 16; 1 page
    - Paris, 1907 March 25; 2 pages
    - Paris, 1907 April; 3 pages
    - Paris, 1907 April 15; 1 page
    - Paris, 1907 May 01; 1 page
      Autograph card, envelope
    - Paris, 1907 May 09; 1 page
    - Annecy, 1907 July 28; 1 page
    - Zermatt, 1907 August 11; 1 page
    - Meiringen, 1907 August 19; 2 pages
    - Montreux, 1907 August 23; 1 page
    - Lausanne, 1907 August 27; 1 page
    - Ouchy, 1907 August 31; 1 page
    - Paris, 1907 September 06; 1 page
    - Paris, 1907 October 12; 1 page
    - Paris, 1907 November 10; 1 page
    - Paris, 1907 November 25; 1 page
    - Paris, 1907 December 05; 1 page
  - Letters from Dukas to Poujaud (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Paris, 1908 February; 2 pages
    - Paris, 1908 February 10; 2 pages
    - Paris, 1908 February 12; 3 pages
    - Nice, 1908 March 26; 1 page
    - Èze, 1908 March 28; 1 page
      Autograph postcard signed, Autograph letter signed by Albeniz
    - Nice, 1908 April 06; 1 page
    - Nice, 1908 July 27; 1 page
    - St. Cloud, 1908 August 12; 1 page
    - Paris, 1908 September 01; 1 page
    - Paris, 1908 September 21; 1 page
    - Paris, 1908 October 06; 1 page
    - Paris, 1908 October 15; 1 page
    - Paris, 1908 October 23; 1 page
    - Paris, 1908 October 26; 1 page
    - Paris, 1908 October 30; 2 pages
    - Brussels, 1908 December 11; 1 page
    - Brussels, 1908 December 14; 1 page
    - Brussels, 1908 December 18; 1 page
  - Letters from Dukas to Poujaud (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Paris, 1909 May 05; 2 pages
    - Paris, 1909 May 19; 1 page
    - Paris, 1909 July 29; 1 page
    - Paris, 1909 August 18; 1 page
    - Paris, 1909 August 30; 1 page
    - Paris, 1909 September 14; 1 page
    - Paris, 1909 September 22; 1 page
    - Paris, 1909 October; 2 pages
    - Paris, 1910 March; 1 page
    - Paris, 1910 March 26; 1 page
    - Paris, 1910 April 01; 1 page
    - Salzburg, 1910 August 11; 1 page
    - Salzburg, 1910 August 22; 1 page
    - Paris, 1910 September 05; 1 page
    - Paris, 1910 November 27; 1 page
    - Paris, 1911 May 06; 1 page
    - Paris, 1911 June 09; 1 page
    - Paris, 1911 June 10; 3 pages
    - Paris, 1911 July 31; 3 pages
    - Paris, 1911 August 26; 1 page
    - Paris, 1911 September 04; 1 page
    - Paris, 1911 September 26; 1 page
    - Paris, 1911 December 19; 1 page
  - Letters from Dukas to Poujaud (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Paris, 1912 February 19; 2 pages
    - Paris, 1912 February 22; 2 pages
    - Paris, 1912 April 04; 2 pages
    - Paris, 1912 April 30; 2 pages
    - Paris, 1912 May 03; 3 pages
    - Paris, 1912 May 14; 3 pages
    - Paris, 1912 May 17; 2 pages
    - Paris, 1912 May 20; 2 pages
    - Paris, 1912 May 23; 2 pages
    - Avignon, 1912 May 30; 1 page
    - Arles, 1912 June 03; 1 page
    - Toulon, 1912 June 03; 1 page
    - Aix-en-Provence, 1912 June 07; 1 page
    - Paris, 1912 June 10; 1 page
    - Paris, 1912 June 24; 2 pages
    - Paris, 1912 July 05; 2 pages
    - Paris, 1912 July 13; 3 pages
    - Paris, 1912 July 18; 4 pages
    - Paris, 1912 August 01; 1 page
    - Paris, 1912 August 04; 1 page
    - Paris, 1912 August 23; 1 page
    - Paris, 1912 August 26; 1 page
    - Paris, 1912 August 26; 1 page
    - Paris, 1912 September 03; 1 page
    - Paris, 1912 September 13; 1 page
    - Paris, 1912 September 14; 1 page
    - Milan, 1912 September 21; 1 page
    - Florence, 1912 September 28; 1 page
    - Florence, 1912 October 01; 1 page
    - Florence, 1912 October 02; 1 page
    - Florence, 1912 October 05; 1 page
    - Pisa, 1912 October 07; 1 page
    - Paris, 1912 October; 1 page
    - Paris, 1912 October 12; 1 page
    - Paris, 1912 November 21; 1 page
    - Paris, 1912 December; 1 page
    - Paris, 1912 December 24; 1 page
  - Letters from Dukas to Poujaud (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Paris, 1913 February 26; 2 pages
    - Paris, 1913 March 08; 2 pages
    - Paris, 1913 April 02; 1 page
    - Paris, 1913 April 07; 3 pages
    - Paris, 1913 April 20 or 27; 1 page
    - Moulins, 1913 May 20; 1 page
    - Nîmes, 1913 May 22; 1 page
    - Pont du Gard, 1913 May 25; 1 page
    - Aigues, 1913 May 26; 1 page
    - Toulons, 1913 May 28; 1 page
    - Paris, 1913 June 04; 1 page
    - Paris, 1913 June 08; 2 pages
    - Paris, 1913 June 10; 1 page
    - Paris, 1913 July 12; 2 pages
    - Paris, 1913 July 15; 1 page
      Autograph postcard signed, envelope
    - Paris, 1913 July 20; 1 page
    - Paris, 1913 August 05; 1 page
    - Paris, 1913 September 06; 1 page
    - Paris, 1913 September 24; 3 pages
    - Paris, 1913 October 01; 1 page
  - Letters from Dukas to Poujaud (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Paris, 1915 January 11; 6 pages
    - Paris, 1915 January 26; 8 pages
    - Paris, 1915 February 12; 8 pages
    - Paris, 1915 February 27; 8 pages
    - Paris, 1915 March 11; 8 pages
    - Paris, 1915 March 21; 8 pages
    - Paris, 1915 April 08; 6 pages
    - Paris, 1915 April 21; 6 pages
    - Paris, 1915 May 08; 8 pages
    - Paris, 1915 May 20; 6 pages
    - Paris, 1915 June 10; 8 pages
    - Paris, 1915 June 24; 8 pages
    - Paris, 1915 July 23; 8 pages
    - Paris, 1915 August 10; 8 pages
    - Paris, 1915 August 16; 2 pages
    - Paris, 1915 September 04; 4 pages
    - Paris, 1915 September 17; 1 page
    - Paris, 1915 September 23; 2 pages
    - Paris, 1915 September 28; 2 pages
    - Paris, 1915 November 10; 2 pages
    - Paris, 1915 November 25; 2 pages
    - Paris, 1915 December 08; 1 page
    - Paris, 1915 December 15; 1 page
    - Paris, 1915 December 21; 2 pages
    - Paris, 1915 December 22; 1 page
  - Letters from Dukas to Poujaud (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Paris, 1916 February 27; 1 page
    - Paris, 1916 March; 1 page
      Autograph Itinerary
    - Paris, 1916 March 03; 1 page
    - Paris, 1916 March 11; 3 pages
    - Paris, 1916 March 18; 3 pages
    - Avignon, 1916 May 12; 2 pages
    - Vaucluse, 1916 May 13; 1 page
    - Montpellier, 1916 May 17; 1 page
    - Montpellier, 1916 May 20; 2 pages
    - Nîmes, 1916 May 20; 2 pages
    - Nîmes, 1916 May 22; 1 page
      Autograph postcard
    - Moulins, 1916 May 26; 1 page
    - Paris, 1916 June 10; 2 pages
    - Paris, 1916 June 24; 1 page
    - Paris, 1916 July 20; 10 pages
    - Paris, 1916 July 31; 7 pages
    - Clisson, 1916 August 09; 2 pages
    - Clisson, 1916 August 11; 1 page
    - Paris, 1916 August 18; 1 page
    - Paris, 1916 August 31; 3 pages
    - Paris, 1916 September 27; 1 page
    - Paris, 1916 September 30; 1 page
    - Paris, 1916 October 10; 1 page
    - Paris, 1916 October 20; 2 pages
    - Paris, 1916 November 01; 1 page
    - Paris, 1916 November 16; 1 page
    - Paris, 1916 December 01; 1 page
    - Paris, 1916 December 12; 1 page
    - Paris, 1916 December 27; 1 page
  - Letters from Dukas to Poujaud (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Paris, 1917 January 17; 1 page
    - Paris, 1917 January 23; 1 page
    - Paris, 1917 February 21; 1 page
    - Ste. Maxime, 1917 March 07; 4 pages
    - Ste. Maxime, 1917 March 15; 1 page
    - Ste. Maxime, 1917 March 16; 1 page
    - Ste. Maxime, 1917 March 19; 4 pages
    - Ste. Maxime, 1917 April 02; 4 pages
    - Ste. Maxime, 1917 April 16; 4 pages
    - Ste. Maxime, 1917 April 26; 1 page
    - Paris, 1917 May 01; 3 pages
      Autograph letter signed, envelope, page of dealer's catalog
    - Paris, 1917 May 24; 1 page
    - Paris, 1917 June 07; 1 page
    - Paris, 1917 June 21; 2 pages
    - Paris, 1917 July 13; 1 page
    - Paris, 1917 July 25; 1 page
    - Paris, 1917 July 30; 1 page
    - Paris, 1917 August 15; 1 page
    - Paris, 1917 August 24; 1 page
    - Paris, 1917 September 04; 1 page
    - Paris, 1917 September 11; 1 page
    - Paris, 1917 October 02; 1 page
    - Paris, 1917 October 15; 1 page
    - Paris, 1917 October 29; 1 page
    - Paris, 1917 November 07; 3 pages
    - Paris, 1917 November 14; 1 page
    - Paris, 1917 December 05; 1 page
    - Paris, 1917 December 20; 1 page
    - Paris, 1917 December 23; 1 page
    - Paris, 1917 December 31; 1 page
  - Letters from Dukas to Poujaud (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Paris, 1918 March 04; 1 page
    - Paris, 1918 March 12; 1 page
    - Paris, 1918 March 26; 1 page
    - Paris, 1918 April 03; 1 page
    - Paris, 1918 April 07; 1 page
    - Paris, 1918 April 23; 4 pages
    - Paris, 1918 May 10; 3 pages
    - St. Brévin, 1918 May 24; 1 page
    - St. Brévin, 1918 May 28; 4 pages
    - Paris, 1918 June 10; 2 pages
    - Paris, 1918 June 13; 3 pages
    - Hossegor, 1918 July 21; 4 pages
    - Hossegor, 1918 August 03; 4 pages
    - Hossegor, 1918 August 22; 5 pages
    - Hossegor, 1918 September 15; 4 pages
    - Paris, 1918 September 24; 1 page
    - Paris, 1918 October 06; 1 page
    - Paris, 1918 October 17; 2 pages
    - Paris, 1918 October 29; 2 pages
    - Paris, 1918 November 09; 1 page
    - Paris, 1918 December 02; 1 page
    - Paris, 1918 December 13; 1 page
  - Letters from Dukas to Poujaud (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Paris, 1919 January 15; 1 page
      Autograph letter signed, program, tickets, envelope
    - Paris, 1919 January 27; 1 page
    - Paris, 1919 February 04; 1 page
    - Paris, 1919 April 06; 1 page
    - Paris, 1919 April 13; 1 page
    - Lorient, 1919 May 10; 1 page
    - Le Mans, 1919 May 16; 2 pages
    - Paris, 1919 May 20; 1 page
    - Paris, 1919 June 25; 4 pages
    - London, 1919 July 18; 2 pages
    - Paris, 1919 August 03; 4 pages
    - Paris, 1919 September 05; 1 page
    - Paris, 1919 September 10; 1 page
    - Nice, 1919 October 17; 1 page
    - Nice, 1919 October 31; 4 pages
    - Cannes, 1919 November 22; 4 pages
    - Cannes, 1919 December 14; 1 page
    - Paris, 1919 December 19; 1 page
  - Letters from Dukas to Poujaud (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Paris, 1920 ??; 1 page
      Manuscript; epitaph in English
    - Paris, 1920 February 07; 1 page
    - Paris, 1920 February 13; 1 page
    - Villefranche, 1920 February 20; 1 page
    - Villefranche, 1920 March 06; 1 page
    - Villefranche, 1920 March 08; 1 page
    - Villefranche, 1920 March 14; 2 pages
    - Villefranche, 1920 April 02; 2 pages
    - Villefranche, 1920 May 06; 1 page
    - Villefranche, 1920 May 15; 1 page
    - Paris, 1920 June 19; 1 page
    - Paris, 1920 June 21; 1 page
    - Paris, 1920 July 01; 1 page
    - Paris, 1920 July 04; 1 page
    - Paris, 1920 August 07; 4 pages
    - Le Mans, 1920 August 13; 1 page
    - Paris, 1920 September 12; 3 pages
    - Paris, 1920 September 20; 1 page
    - Paris, 1920 November 09; 1 page
    - Paris, 1920 November 10; 1 page
  - Letters from Dukas to Poujaud (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Paris, 1921 January 01; 4 pages
    - Nice, 1921 January 20; 10 pages
    - Villefranche, 1921 February 18; 1 page
    - Paris, 1921 February 22; 1 page
    - Paris, 1921 March 15; 1 page
    - Paris, 1921 March 23; 1 page
    - Paris, 1921 March 26; 1 page
    - Villefranche, 1921 April 10; 1 page
    - Paris, 1921 April 18; 1 page
    - Paris, 1921 April 26; 1 page
    - Paris, 1921 April 29; 1 page
      Autograph card signed, envelope
    - Paris, 1921 May 05; 1 page
    - Paris, 1921 June 01; 1 page
    - Paris, 1921 June 20; 1 page
    - Hore, 1921 August 11; 1 page
    - Hardelot, 1921 September 15; 2 pages
    - Paris, 1921 December 10; 1 page
  - Letters from Dukas to Poujaud (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Paris, 1922 January 26; 1 page
      Autograph letter signed, Autograph card signed, envelope
    - Royan, 1922 May; 1 page
    - Lille, 1922 May 21; 1 page
    - Amiens, 1922 May 22; 2 pages
    - Lille, 1922 June 05; 2 pages
    - Royan, 1922 June 28; 4 pages
    - Royan, 1922 July 30; 2 pages
    - Fountainbleau, 1922 August 18; 1 page
    - Fountainbleau, 1922 September 28; 1 page
    - Royan, 1922 October; 1 page
    - Paris, 1922 November 29; 1 page
    - Paris, 1922 December 06; 1 page
  - Letters from Dukas to Poujaud (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Paris, 1923 February 20; 1 page
    - Calais, 1923 April; 1 page
    - Lille, 1923 April 22; 1 page
    - Amiens, 1923 May 25; 1 page
    - Lille, 1923 May 27; 1 page
    - Royan, 1923 June 05; 1 page
    - Royan, 1923 June 06; 1 page
    - Royan, 1923 June 25; 1 page
    - Royan, 1923 August 03; 1 page
    - Royan, 1923 August 21; 1 page
    - Royan, 1923 August 28; 2 pages
    - Paris, 1923 October 31; 1 page
    - Royan, 1923 December 06; 2 pages
      Autograph letter signed, ticket, envelope
  - Letters from Dukas to Poujaud (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Paris, 1924 March 25; 1 page
    - Avignon, 1924 May 20; 1 page
    - Montpellier, 1924 May 30; 2 pages
    - Royan, 1924 June 08; 1 page
    - Royan, 1924 June 14; 1 page
    - Royan, 1924 June 21; 1 page
    - Royan, 1924 July 24; 2 pages
    - Royan, 1924 September 04; 2 pages
    - Paris, 1924 September 11; 1 page
    - Royan, 1924 September 26; 1 page
    - Royan, 1924 October 15; 2 pages
    - Royan, 1924 October 21; 1 page
  - Letters from Dukas to Poujaud (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Royan, 1925 February 12; 1 page
    - Royan, 1925 April 14; 2 pages
    - Avignon, 1925 May 17; 1 page
    - Cette, 1925 May 28; 1 page
    - Royan, 1925 June io; 2 pages
    - Royan, 1925 June 23; 1 page
    - Royan, 1925 October 11; 1 page
    - Royan, 1925 October 14; 1 page
    - Paris, 1925 October 30; 1 page
    - Paris, 1925 November 25; 1 page
    - Paris, 1925 December 20; 1 page
    - Paris, 1925 December 26; 1 page
  - Letters from Dukas to Poujaud (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Paris, 1926 --- 12; 1 page
    - Paris, 1926 February 07; 1 page
    - Paris, 1926 April 10; 1 page
    - Gare de Cham, 1926 May 06; 1 page
    - Gare de Cham, 1926 May 11; 1 page
    - Nimes, 1926 May; 1 page
    - Cette, 1926 May 21; 1 page
    - Royan, 1926 June 03; 1 page
    - Saint-Malo, 1926 July 13; 1 page
    - Paris, 1926 July 26; 4 pages
    - Royan, 1926 August 14; 4 pages
    - Paris, 1926 October 08; 1 page
  - Letters from Dukas to Poujaud (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Paris, 1927 --- 27; 1 page
    - Paris, 1927 February 07; 1 page
    - Paris, 1927 March 22; 1 page
    - Paris, 1927 March 29; 1 page
    - Paris, 1927 March 29; 1 page
    - Augoulaille, 1927 May 24; 1 page
    - Toulouse, 1927 June 01; 3 pages
    - Paris, 1927 June 08; 1 page
    - Royan, 1927 July 28; 4 pages
    - Paris, 1927 November 22; 1 page
    - Paris, 1927 December 03; 1 page
    - Paris, 1927 December 05; 1 page
    - Paris, 1927 December 28; 1 page
  - Letters from Dukas to Poujaud (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Tours, 1928 May 27; 2 pages
    - Pau, 1928 June 03; 1 page
    - Paris, 1928 June 29; 1 page
    - Paris, 1928 August 03; 2 pages
    - Paris, 1928 August 13; 4 pages
    - Paris, 1928 September 10; 2 pages
  - Letters from Dukas to Poujaud (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Paris, 1929 April 02; 2 pages
    - Paris, 1929 April 13; 4 pages
    - Paris, 1929 May 08; 3 pages
    - Tours, 1929 May 19; 1 page
    - Pau, 1929 May 26; 1 page
    - Paris, 1929 June 06; 4 pages
    - Paris, 1929 June 30; 4 pages
    - Paris, 1929 July 08; 2 pages
    - Paris, 1929 July 26; 2 pages
    - Paris, 1929 August 05; 4 pages
    - Royan, 1929 August 15; 1 page
    - Paris, 1929 August 25; 2 pages
    - Paris, 1929 October 31; 4 pages
    - Paris, 1929 December 15; 4 pages
  - Letters from Dukas to Poujaud (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Paris, 1932 May 29; 4 pages
    - Adriana, 1932 August 01; 1 page
    - Royan, 1932 September 01; 2 pages
    - Paris, 1932 September 24; 2 pages
    - Paris, 1932 November 19; 6 pages
    - Paris, 1923 December 30; 1 page
  - Letters from Dukas to Poujaud (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Paris, 1933 February 09; 4 pages
    - Paris, 1933 June 05; 2 pages
    - Royan, 1933 July 15; 4 pages
    - Royan, 1933 September 09; 4 pages
    - Royan, 1933 September 22; 2 pages
    - Paris, 1933 November 29; 4 pages
  - Letters from Dukas to Poujaud (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Royan, 1934 February 07; 1 page
    - Paris, 1934 March 12; 8 pages
    - Paris, 1934 May 10; 1 page
    - Paris, 1934 July 23; 6 pages
    - Paris, 1934 October 30; 4 pages
    - Paris, 1934 December 18; 2 pages
  - Letters from Dukas to Poujaud (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Paris, 1935 March 10; 4 pages
      Autograph letter signed, photo of A. Dukas
  - Letters from Dukas to Poujaud (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Paris, 19?? February 08; 1 page
- Letters from Poujaud to Dukas, Series II
  - Letters from Poujaud to Dukas (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Guéret, 1906 July 24; 4 pages
    - Paris, 1907 November 26; 3 pages
    - Paris, 1908 December 15; 1 page
    - Paris, 1910 April 30; 1 page
  - Letters from Poujaud to Dukas (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Paris, 1912 June 06; 2 pages
    - Paris, 1912 June 23; 4 pages
    - Paris, 1912 July 04; 3 pages
    - Paris, 1912 July 08; 1 page
    - Paris, 1912 July 14; 4 pages
    - Paris, 1912 August 23; 1 page
  - Letters from Poujaud to Dukas (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Paris, 1913 April 06; 2 pages
    - Paris, 1913 June 03; 2 pages
  - Letters from Poujaud to Dukas (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Paris, 1914 May 20; 2 pages
    - Paris, 1914 May 28; 1 page
    - Paris, 1914 June 26; 2 pages
    - Paris, 1914 July 31; 1 page
    - Guéret, 1914 August 06; 4 pages
    - Guéret, 1914 August 12; 4 pages
    - Guéret, 1914 August 19; 4 pages
    - Guéret, 1914 August 26; 4 pages
    - Guéret, 1914 September 02; 4 pages
    - Guéret, 1914 September 09; 4 pages
    - Guéret, 1914 September 20; 4 pages
    - Guéret, 1914 September 27; 4 pages
    - Guéret, 1914 October 03; 4 pages
    - Guéret, 1914 October 09; 4 pages
    - Guéret, 1914 October 16; 4 pages
    - Guéret, 1914 October 24; 4 pages
    - Guéret, 1914 November 07; 4 pages
    - Guéret, 1914 November 08; 4 pages
    - Guéret, 1914 November 20; 4 pages
    - Guéret, 1914 November 29; 4 pages
    - Guéret, 1914 December 24; 4 pages
    - Guéret, 1914 December 25; 4 pages
  - Letters from Poujaud to Dukas (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Guéret, 1915 January 06; 6 pages
    - Guéret, 1915 January 17; 10 pages
    - Guéret, 1915 February 03; 12 pages
    - Guéret, 1915 February 18; 8 pages
    - Guéret, 1915 July 04; 12 pages
    - Guéret, 1915 July 31; 8 pages
    - Guéret, 1915 August 15; 4 pages
    - Guéret, 1915 August 24; 8 pages
    - Paris, 191S September 18; 2 pages
    - Paris, 1915 September 25; 3 pages
    - Paris, 1915 October 21; 2 pages
  - Letters from Poujaud to Dukas (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Guéret, 1916 March 27; 3 pages
  - Letters from Poujaud to Dukas (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Paris, 1917 January 19; 3 pages
    - Paris, 1917 January 20; 1 page
    - Paris, 1917 January 24; 2 pages
    - Paris, 1917 March 13; 4 pages
    - Paris, 1917 March 26; 6 pages
    - Paris, 1917 April 09; 6 pages
    - Paris, 1917 April 30; 4 pages
    - Paris, 1917 August 25; 1 page
    - Paris, 1917 October 08; 2 pages
    - Paris, 1917 November 09; 3 pages
    - Paris, 1917 November 15; 3 pages
  - Letters from Poujaud to Dukas (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Paris, 1918 March 04; 3 pages
    - Paris, 1918 March 27; 1 page
    - Paris, 1918 April 03; 1 page
    - Guéret, 1918 April 19; 4 pages
    - Guéret, 1918 May 03; 1 page
    - Guéret, 1918 May 19; 4 pages
    - Guéret, 1918 June 07; 4 pages
    - Guéret, 1918 June 12; 4 pages
    - Guéret, 1918 June 20; 1 page
    - Guéret, 1918 July 04; 4 pages
    - Guéret, 1918 July 27; 8 pages
    - Guéret, 1918 August 16; 4 pages
    - Paris, 1918 October 17; 1 page
    - Paris, 1918 November 10; 1 page
    - Paris, 1918 November 17; 1 page
  - Letters from Poujaud to Dukas (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Paris, 1919 March 26; 1 page
    - Paris, 1919 May 12; 2 pages
    - Guéret, 1919 June 17; 4 pages
    - Guéret, 1919 July 29; 4 pages
    - Guéret, 1919 August 29; 4 pages
    - Paris, 1919 September 10; 1 page
    - Paris, 1919 October 26; 4 pages
    - Paris, 1919 November 19; 4 pages
    - Paris, 1919 December 09; 4 pages
  - Letters from Poujaud to Dukas (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Paris, 1920 February 14; 1 page
    - Paris, 1920 March 23; 6 pages
    - Paris, 1920 April 21; 8 pages
    - Paris, 1920 May 10; 1 page
    - Paris, 1920 May 14; 3 pages
    - Paris, 1920 June 22; 1 page
    - Guéret, 1920 July 22; 4 pages
    - Guéret, 1920 August 24; 6 pages
  - Letters from Poujaud to Dukas (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Paris, 1921 January 08; 10 pages
    - Paris, 1921 January 29; 10 pages
    - Paris, 1921 March 12; 1 page
    - Paris, 1921 March 20; 3 pages
    - Paris, 1921 March 25; 2 pages
    - Paris, 1921 April 07; 4 pages
    - Paris, 1921 May 05; 4 pages
    - Paris, 1921 June 21; 4 pages
    - Paris, 1921 August 17; 1 page